Portfolio: cslyons1.github.io/csl.github.io · LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/cody-lyons

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Resourceful problem-solver with a decade of project management experience seeking to transition my high-level communication, design, and data analysis skills to a full-time role in the field of UX/UI design; interpreting and making inferences from data while visually conceptualizing innovative marketing materials.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Regency Commercial Construction**

Dec. 2019 - Jan. 2023

Assistant Project Manager

Beltsville, MD

Executed project management duties on multiple concurring projects within diverse teams of executives, architects, and engineers including:

- Utilized dashboards and reports to monitor project data and actively adjust schedules, budgets, and scopes of work, ensuring that project milestones were met and resulting in early project turnover and increased profits
- Identified and presented key project metrics to stakeholders conveying an overview of relevant project updates
- Employed version control practices to develop, organize, and distribute project information to project teams
- Developed and perpetually updated comprehensive reports using project data including spreadsheets and logs to track contract document submissions, material acquisition statuses, requests for information, and change proposals
- Served as liaison between stakeholders and subcontractors, maintaining communication between all parties, and facilitated positive working relationships
- Generated and presented proposal documents to stakeholders' executive management teams

**ADP Consultants** Feb. 2019 - Dec. 2019

Assistant Project Manager

Capitol Heights, MD

Performed project management duties and assisted company owner in the following:

- Tracked key project milestones and prepared status update documentation for presentation to stakeholders
- Created and reviewed project-specific documents for compliance with contract documents, identified discrepancies, and implemented solutions to address non-conformances
- Facilitated communication with project stakeholders and maintained positive working relationships

Sept. 2016 - Aug. 2018 **Clark Concrete Contractors** 

**Quality Control Engineer** 

Bethesda, MD

Collaborated with stakeholders to managed project-specific quality control procedures including:

- Implemented project-specific document version control and access structures to regulate the updating and distribution of project documents between stakeholders and project teams
- Developed and implemented Quality Control Plans while presenting related project data reports to stakeholders
- Reviewed and issued contract document submissions for approval

## **Hillis-Carnes Engineering Associates**

Jul. 2007 - Sept. 2016

Engineering Technician

Annapolis Junction, MD

- Developed detailed reports documenting operations, project and material-related issues, and solution proposals
- Upheld communication between stakeholders, contractors, and third-party consultants

# **SKILLS**

Python, SQL, GIMP, Photoshop, Microsoft Office, Google Sheets, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Web Scraping, Creative Problem Solving, Effective Communication

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION**

## The Pennsylvania State University

Bachelor of Science, Integrated Social Sciences

## **Google Data Analytics**

Professional Certificate in Data Analytics from Google